reecebaptie@gmail.com

(+27) 071 350 6692

Reece Baptie

Durban,

KZN,

South Africa.





Software Engineer



I'm passionate professional whose interests lie in learning the latest and greatest technologies whether that's the frontend or backend. I enjoy creating applications that use the latest features in addition to being user friendly. I am an adaptable and self-motivated learner.

I am experienced in web and native applications development. I have advanced exposure to the Microsoft 365 stack by have building, deployed and supported solutions. I am a certified Microsoft Associate Developer and enjoy using the lates avaliable tools and technologies provided by Microsoft and their partners.

Skills

Programming Languages:

React, JavaScript, C#, Java, SQL

Frameworks:

SPFx, .NET, Android, Angular

Tools:

Git, npm, nvm, PowerShell

Education

Clifton College (2010-2014) Bachelor's Degree

Varsity College (2017-2019) Bachelor's Degree (BCAD) of Computer Science in Application Development

Certifications

MICROSOFT CERTIFICATION, Microsoft 365 Certified: Developer Associate (2021)

Soft Skills

Teamwork, Independent, Communication, Problem solving, Remote worker

Work Experience

Clifton School (2015 - 2019)

Coach, School

- Coached schoolboys in Cricket, Rugby, and Hockey
- Team management and preparation for practice sessions and matches
- Team selection requires good communication with players and giving them clear reasoning and improvements

Goal Pro (2019 - 2020)

Native Android developer

- Created a native android application Goal Pro Solutions for the non-profit organisation Goal Pro
- Full stack developer
- Took the application through each phase of the project from planning, developing and keeping the client up to date and in the loop, to launching and maintaining the application
- Database administrator, application uses Google's Firebase storage and authentications

Pilotfish (2020 – present)

Modern Workplace Developer

- Pilotfish is a Microsoft (MS) partner who and creates applications on MS SharePoint as well as providing support for their clients on the MS environment.
- I develop applications for SharePoint 2013, 2016, 2019 using JavaScript
- I develop applications for SharePoint Online using SharePoint Framework (SPfx) web parts with React
- Utilising SharePoint Designer workflows for on-premises environments.
- I develop applications which extend functionality for SharePoint using the MS Power Platform (PowerApps, Power Automate, Power Bi, Power Virtual Agents, and Power Pages)
- Develop applications for MS Teams
- Support clients as a MS Global Admin for on-premises and online environments
- Utilising the MS Amin Centre to support clients and manage users.
- Utilising MS Azure to manage users and applications